SAMUEL MUNGAI NJOGU P.O. BOX 64-20305 WANJOHI

Tel: 0726-774768

Email: mungai4seal@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

I am a skilled individual who is always ready to give his all in all task given a challenging and rewarding environment towards the attainment of set goals. I have an in-depth knowledge in all management operations, people management skills, work planning and measurement of results in addition to my excellent analytical skills which have served me well in the past. I have a wide knowledge in operations management; my goal is to deliver in an environment with a never ending innovation and contribute effectively to organizational success.

Personal Details:

o AGE: 30 Years

ID Number: 27752866Marital Status: Married

Education & Professional Qualifications:

- o Bachelor of Arts in Project planning and management- University of Nairobi November 2012 –May 2015.
- Diploma in food science and technology, (KNEC EXAM) The Kenya polytechnic university college.2009-2011 – CREDIT PASS.
- Computer packages (MS OFFICE) kikuyu youth training college.;june2009-aug2009
- Kenya certificate of secondary Education, Ol'kalou secondary school B-(minus);2005-2008

Kev Professional Skills

- Proven administrative, leadership and management ability in areas of strategic planning and organizational development.
- Ability to devise and implement resource plans, particularly in areas of service improvement, staff development and change management.
- Ability to work on own initiative, prioritize work, handle pressure and takeday to day decision on the smooth running of the organization.
- Ability to develop, monitor and maintain management information systems and procedures.

Page 1

- Ability to communicate effectively in person, in writing and over the telephone with individuals as well as external organizations, analyze and interpret complex information and produce clear verbal and written reports.
- o Ability to lead, motivate, train and contribute to theteam.

Key Professional Trainings Attended:

- Integrated management system auditor (ISO 9001:2008, ISO 22000:2005 with PAS 22O) FEB 2013- SGS
- o FSSC (ISO 22000:2005 &PAS 220 course) FEB 2013-SGS
- o Supervisory skills development- NOV 2013- THE ACT INSTITUTE
- Lean Six Sigma- yellow Belt Champion-July 2013 -KENYA INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT(KIM)
- o Food safety (FSSC 22000) & Quality Management (ISO 9001) system internal auditors training- 2014- Millennium management consultants ltd
- Occupational Safety and health committees training- April 2012- SHEQ management Systems.
- o First Aid Training (full course)- Primatech management systems 2018
- Fire safety and management training- Primatech management systems 2018
- Technical representative at KEBS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PRODUCTION MANAGER AQUAMIST LIMITED 01/07/2015- PRESENT

- 1. Directing and coordinating activities of businesses and departments concerned with the production, pricing, sales, and/or distribution of products
- 2. Managing staff, preparing work schedules and assigning specific duties
- 3. Establishing and implementing departmental policies, goals, objectives, and procedures.
- 4. Determining staffing requirements, and interviewing, hiring and training new employees, or overseeing those personnel processes.
- 5. Overseeing activities directly related to making products
- 6. Directing and coordinating organization's operational procedures in a way that maximizes resources use.
- 7. Managing the movement of goods into and out of production facilities
- 8. Developing and implementing product marketing strategies including advertising campaigns and sales promotions

- 9. Dealing with other regulatory bodies like KEBS,KRA, Municipal council, and other agencies in the horticulture industry
- 10. Participated and engaged staff in acquiring FSMS and QMS

PRODUCTION SUPERVISOR KEVIAN KENYA LIMITED JAN 2013 TO 30/06/2015 DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Production planning for Afia fruit drink, peek n peel Juices and Mt-Kenyan water, inclusive of startup management, daily targets and cost management
- Supervise production line operations in accordance with plant policies and procedures
- Train and coach production line employees
- Ensuring ISO standard specifications are followed by all the staffs
- Responsible for shift schedule that include: work stationassignments(rotation),
 employee training, reporting time management and shift rotations
- Coordinate production start- ups, shut down and change overs
- Coordinate with human resource for appropriate staffing levels
- Responsible for production in meeting production goals
- Ensuring quality control makes adjustments as necessary produce product within specifications
- Championing Kaizen
- Training staffs on lean manufacturing methodology

PRODUCTION SUPERVISOR.

AQUAMIST MINERALWATER COMPANY LTD -NOV 2011- DEC 2012 DUTIES & RESPONSIBILITIES INCLUDED

- Supervised Laboratory personnel to ensure proper daily analysis of mineral water tests including total dissolved solids, pH, conductivity and microbiological analysis
- Supervised water filtration systems cleaning programs including back washing of sand filters, carbon filters and the micro filters.
- Rejected products outside specifications
- Improved the operational systems, processes and policies in support of the organizational mission.
- Supervised products movement into and out of production facilities
- Played a significant role in long term planning, including an initiative geared towards operational excellence.
- Ensuring factory cleanness at all times of operations
- Enforcing requirements of the ISO standards to ensure the highest quality of mineral water
- Reconsolidation of production output/compiling daily production to the top management

OUALITY ANALYST (CONTROLLER).

PROCTOR & ALLAN (E.A) LTD Aug 2010-to Dec 2010.

Duties & Responsibilities included:

- Control of production process of breakfast cereal and pet foods
- o Weekly microbiological analysis of factory processing surfaces.
- o Receiving of packaging materials and analyzing their quality
- Ensuring proper processing procedures
- Receiving of raw materials and analyzing their quality such as moisture content and contaminants
- o Chemical analysis of food fillers, pet foods and breakfast cereals.
- o Involvement in new product development and research.
- o Maintenance of hygiene and sanitation in the factory

CURRENT RENUMERATION

This can be provided upon request

INTERESTS:

- o Dairy farming
- o Research and innovation
- Computers

REFEREES

Please feel free to contact the under mentioned concerning my competence, work ethic and performance.

FRANK MWANGI KINYUA

Process and maintenance engineer Kevian Kenya Limited P.O Box 25290 Nairobi Nairobi

Tel: +254 723 516656

PETER KABUGA WAITHAKA

Production manager Kevian Kenya Limited P.o box 25290 Nairobi Tel: +254 724 778933

JOSEPH WAIHARO NJOROGE

Procurement coordinator Kikuyu Water P.o.Box 880 Kikuyu

Tel: +254 725725927